<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Uptonian Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://tupton.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tupton.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-19T22:04:44-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://tupton.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Upton]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading My News]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/07/reading-my-news/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-12T18:12:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/07/reading-my-news</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve used Google Reader for a long time, but I’ve never been completely satisfied with using it to
read and keep up with RSS feeds. Apps like <a href="http://flipboard.com/">Flipboard</a> on the iPad provide a better
reading experience for traditionally “newsy” outlets – I enjoy flipping through the feeds from <em>The
New Yorker</em>, <em>The Economist</em>, and <em>The Atlantic</em> – but following feeds where every item is of
personal interest to me doesn’t make much sense in that context, and it’s iOS-only. I had used
<a href="http://netnewswireapp.com/">NetNewsWire</a> a few times in the past, but I never stuck with it for some reason. It’s
a great app, but I would constantly get distracted by that big red badge with a huge number of
unread items in it.</p>

<p>I realized that my problem wasn’t really the apps I was using. What really made reading my feeds
imperfect – or even tedious – was the number of feeds I had and <em>how</em> I was reading them. I decided
to revisit NetNewsWire and check out an app on iOS that I had heard great things about.</p>

<h2 id="prune">Prune</h2>

<p>The first key to revamping my news reading was pruning my subscriptions. I had way too many
high-traffic feeds, and I wasn’t even reading 1% of some of them. I would go through all my feeds
and folders and mark everything as read every few days<sup id="fnref:too-long"><a href="#fn:too-long" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> just to keep up and feel like I
wasn’t overwhelmed.</p>

<p>I got rid of feeds from sites like <a href="http://www.lamebook.com/">Lamebook</a>, which is hilarious, but I don’t need to
read every single item, and <a href="http://www.absolutepunk.net/">Absolute Punk</a>, which is a great source for music news, but I only
want to read a very small portion of those stories. I get my fix from these sites by visiting them
every few days, not by trying to forge through a murky river of hundreds of RSS items that I don’t
want to read.</p>

<p>I now have 26 feeds in 8 categories,<sup id="fnref:cross-link"><a href="#fn:cross-link" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> down from twice that before pruning. This is
manageable. 50+ high-traffic feeds are not. I can read the items from these feeds quickly, and I
can finally read “all items” without becoming overwhelmed.</p>

<h2 id="netnewswire-revisited-again">NetNewsWire, revisited (again)</h2>

<p>I mentioned that I had used NetNewsWire before, but it never stuck. A couple of weeks ago, I saw
<a href="http://collindonnell.com/2012/06/29/my-netnewswire-window/">this NetNewsWire setup</a> and knew I had to try it. <code>⌘-⇧-R</code> and <code>⌘-/</code> are now my favorite
keyboard shortcuts. Refresh, and then scroll through my unread river of items. I sort
chronologically so I read posts “in order,” but I don’t think it actually matters much at all.
Since I have a low number of feeds, it usually only takes a few minutes to travel through these
unread items. Any links to things I want to check out in more depth later get a quick <code>^-P</code> to send
to Instapaper.</p>

<h2 id="reeder-on-mobile">Reeder on mobile</h2>

<p>I was recently on vacation without my MacBook, but I had my iPad and still wanted to keep up with my
news and feeds. There are plenty of other times that I’m without my computer but have a chance to
catch up on my reading. I figured (or hoped, really) that I could make the experience of reading
news on my iPhone and iPad just as great as it is with NetNewsWire at my desk.</p>

<p>I had heard great things about <a href="http://reederapp.com/">Reeder</a> on iOS, but I was skeptical that it could work for
me. It turns out I can get nearly the same river of news setup as NetNewsWire in Reeder. Unread
items can be sorted in chronological order, and moving to the next item is just a matter of swiping
up.</p>

<p>The end result is that I have a streamlined way to catch up on news that’s important to me as
quickly as possible, no matter where I am. I spend less time fiddling with news items I don’t really
care about, less time out of my day being distracted by the latest hot article,<sup id="fnref:distract"><a href="#fn:distract" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> and more
time doing what I want and need to do.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:too-long">
      <p>I did this ritual for far too long before I realized it needed to end. Old habits die hard. <a href="#fnref:too-long" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:cross-link">
      <p>I’ve noticed that a lot of sites and blogs I read will “cross-post” each other’s items. This sounds like it might be annoying to have to read about the same things in multiple places, but usually one of two things happens: either the cross-posting contains a bit of insightful back-and-forth on a topic, or multiple people link to a great article elsewhere that I know I need to check out. I get to follow great discussions and the cream of the hot topic crop rises to the top of my news readers. Win-win for me. <a href="#fnref:cross-link" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:distract">
      <p>If only I could figure out how to stop checking <a href="http://stellar.io/">Stellar</a> so much.<a href="#fnref:distract" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aeropress]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/07/aeropress/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-01T00:07:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/07/aeropress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8161/7476327252_8acfa39cbb_z_d.jpg" alt="Aeropress" /></p>

<p>I don’t think I’ll be using my Keurig much anymore.</p>

<p>I’m extremely late to this party, but I only recently discovered Aerobie’s <a href="http://aerobie.com/products/aeropress.htm">Aeropress</a>
coffee maker.  Yes, the company that created <a href="http://aerobie.com/products/pro.htm">those amazing ring-shaped flying discs</a>
also sells a weird-looking coffee maker. This plunger-like contraption helps to brew what is
probably the best cup of coffee I have ever tasted.</p>

<p>At first glance, it’s similar to a French press, but because the coffee is forced through a paper
filter instead of a coarser wire mesh, there is little to no sediment in the resulting liquid. The
coffee is described as “espresso-strength,” and I drink it as an Americano by adding a volume of
water equal to two times the amount of espresso. I’ve made Aeropress coffe with dark and lighter
roasts, and every cup of coffee has been exquisite.</p>

<p>If you enjoy coffee <em>at all</em>, I highly suggest you acquire an Aeropress as soon as possible. Once
you taste its delicious brew, you’ll understand why. It’s inexpensive, quick, easy to clean, and
delicious. There are no downsides.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knowing The Rules]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/06/knowing-the-rules/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T20:55:48-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/06/knowing-the-rules</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You’re likely to be more comfortable with many situations if you know the rules of the environment
you’re in, including knowing its bounds and how flexible they are. </p>

<p>It sounds so obvious when it’s printed on the page in front of you, but if you’re more familiar with
a situation, it frees up your mind to focus on other things that you need to do or are good at.  You
stop worrying about whether you’re within the acceptable bounds of your current situation and just
do what you’re good at. “Apprehension” is usually just a term we use when we come across a situation
that we don’t quite fully understand.</p>

<p>Take, for example, the security lines at most American airports. If you place someone in that
situation who has never been there before, it would most likely be very overwhelming. There are
uniformed people with badges who don’t quite look like police, everyone is taking off their shoes,
but not before they hand two important documents to one of the faux-police, and then you have to
walk next to these weird doorway things but there are two kinds and one you have to pause in the
middle and turn sideways and oh yeah you remembered to take <em>everything</em> out of your pockets before
this, right? It’s overwhelming to someone who’s not familiar. To someone who travels often, however,
it’s positively rote.</p>

<p>Clearly, you don’t need to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Outliers_(book)">spend ten thousand hours</a> going through security lines to
become comfortable with air travel. Even one experience where you’re out of your element but aware
of your surroundings helps to prepare you for the next time. It’s obvious that the more you know
something, the better you are at it. But <em>so many</em> people seem to not take the time to learn the
rules and boundaries and then continually “wing it” while being overly-anxious.</p>

<p>An article I recently read about <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702303836404577474451463041994.html">how some anxiety is necessary</a> might initially seem like
it’s a counterpoint to this, but there’s a big difference between being prepared and being
complacent. Even that article mentions that you have to get the balance just right lest you become
lazy. Sports are a great example here. You have to know the game you’re playing inside and out <em>and</em>
have finely-honed fundamental skills so you can focus most or all of your thinking on strategy or on
the dynamic parts of the game that your instincts cannnot help with.</p>

<p>Even “simple” things, like how to interact in social situations, can be made easier if you think
about the rules. It’s probably not a good idea to talk about that weird rash on your lower back, but
it is a good idea to talk about a great beer you tried recently, or how the playoffs are going, or
that you’re thinking about getting a dog. The basic rule there is “don’t be creepy.”</p>

<p>The hard part is knowing the rules in the first place. That comes through experience, and sometimes
a little research – Googling, asking your friends or family – beforehand comes in handy.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Syntastic]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/05/syntastic/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-20T14:13:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/05/syntastic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love writing with <code>vim</code>, but — for many valid reasons — some people are averse to it. I think the steep (–ish) learning curve has something to do with it, but I think some people really don’t want to give up their IDE. The thing is, <code>vim</code> isn’t <em>just</em> a text editor. You can extend it to do pretty much anything, including features that normally show up in IDEs.</p>

<p>I recently started using <a href="https://github.com/scrooloose/syntastic">syntastic</a>, which is a <code>vim</code> plugin that runs linters or syntax checkers and displays warnings and errors right in your window. IDEs like Eclipse or Xcode provide this syntax-checking for a couple of languages, but syntastic supports many languages and linters out of the box with pluggable support for nearly any language. </p>

<h2 id="setup">Setup</h2>

<p>If you use <a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen">pathogen</a> like every sane <code>vim</code> user does, installing syntastic is just like any other plugin. Clone the repository or create a submodule in <code>bundle/syntastic</code> and you’re ready to go.</p>

<p>I mainly work with Javascript, Python, HTML, and CSS, so that’s what I’ll talk about. It’s worth checking out the syntax checkers in <code>bundle/syntastic/syntax_checkers/</code>, even if you just look at the list of files there. You might have to dive into the files to figure out which linters are actually supported as it’s not clearly documented.</p>

<p>Before we get to configuring individual syntax checkers, syntastic itself has a couple of configuration options. Syntastic has what it refers to as a “mode map”, which is basically just a way to configure which file types are checked. Here is the relevant config option from <a href="https://github.com/tupton/vim-support/blob/master/vimrc#L302">my vimrc</a>:</p>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
<span class="line-number">4</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="vim"><span class="line"><span class="c">&quot; On by default, turn it off for html</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">let</span> <span class="k">g</span>:syntastic_mode_map <span class="p">=</span> { <span class="s1">&#39;mode&#39;</span>: <span class="s1">&#39;active&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class="line">	\ <span class="s1">&#39;active_filetypes&#39;</span>: []<span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class="line">	\ <span class="s1">&#39;passive_filetypes&#39;</span>: [<span class="s1">&#39;html&#39;</span>] }
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<p>The ‘mode’ option set to active means that syntastic is on by default, so we can leave the list of ‘active_filetypes’ empty. The ‘passive_filetypes’ names filetypes that syntastic does not attempt to check. I don’t check HTML files because I mainly work with templates that either can’t or won’t validate with most HTML syntax checkers. If templates use non-standard attributes, it’s hard for a syntax checker to do its job.</p>

<h3 id="python">Python</h3>

<p>Setting up syntastic for use with python was extremely easy. <a href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/pyflakes">pyflakes</a> has relatively sane defaults, so running it with no configuration is more than acceptable. Just install <code>pyflakes</code> with <code>pip install pyflakes</code> and syntastic will automatically do the rest.</p>

<h3 id="javascript">Javascript</h3>

<p>There are a number of Javascript linters, including <a href="http://www.jslint.com/">JS Lint</a> and Google’s <a href="https://developers.google.com/closure/utilities/">Closure linter</a>, but I decided to use the communtiy-driven <a href="http://www.jshint.com/">JS Hint</a>.  JS Hint can be configured with a jshintrc, which just is a JSON object that contains options. There are two categories of options: those that enforce stricter rules than the defaults and those that relax default checks. The <a href="http://www.jshint.com/options/">options page of the jshint website</a> does a great job of explaining each option. You can <a href="https://github.com/tupton/dotfiles/blob/master/jshintrc">view my jshintrc on my Github page</a>. I added a few “enforcing” options, but the only “relaxing” option I use is the “sub” option, which allows subscript notation when accessing properties, e.g. <code>this['domNode']</code> as well as <code>this.domNode</code>.</p>

<h2 id="usage">Usage</h2>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7085/7235544916_6f48ae8f45_o_d.png" alt="syntastic and underscore.js" /></p>

<p>By default, syntastic runs your file through the configured filetype’s linter whenever the buffer is written. If there are errors, they are highlighted inline. When your cursor is on a line with an error, the description of the error is visible in the status line. You can use the <code>:Errors</code> command to open a quickfix window with a list of all errors in the file. Pressing enter on an error will take you to that line in the file. Syntastic uses <a href="http://vimdoc.sourceforge.net/htmldoc/sign.html">vim’s signs</a>, which means that a gutter with a sign appears on the left side of every line with an error on it, making it easy to scan the buffer for errors.</p>

<p>You can configure syntastic in many other ways, including telling it to check a buffer whenever it is opened. I explored the help file (<code>:help syntastic</code>) when I first started using syntastic, and it was incredibly helpful. I encourage anyone who uses syntastic to do the same.</p>

<p>Syntastic has already helped me avoid many typos and silly errors that would ordinarily be hard to track down. It’s an invaluable tool in my workflow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mint]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/04/mint/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-17T18:37:38-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/04/mint</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7180/7089520649_0beff76701_o_d.png" alt="Mint" /></p>

<p>I just started using <a href="http://haveamint.com/">Mint</a> to track statistics on my site. I’ve been using Google Analytics for a long time, and I will continue to do so, but it is definitely geared more towards sites trying to earn money. Mint seemed to offer a more streamlined and customizable interface for people who just want to look at stats.</p>

<p>Mint is a pluggable, extensible stats system. Mint modules are known as “peppers,” and each one provides some small functionality. There is a <a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/4/default/">default pepper</a> that provides some basic stats functionality like page views, unique visitors, search terms that brought those visitors to your site, and which pages they are looking at. There are a large number of official and community peppers over at the Peppermill that offer much more functionality and statistical views.</p>

<h2 id="installation">Installation</h2>

<p>Installing Mint was a breeze. I just followed the simple instructions and I was good to go. If you have unfettered access to your server (via <code>ssh</code>) you should have no issues.</p>

<h3 id="issues-with-modpagespeed">Issues with mod_pagespeed</h3>

<p>I did run into a couple strange display issues when I went to view my Mint stats. Each pane took up the maximum width when it was opened. Even though I could view all my stats, the interface didn’t look good. After posting in the forum and fruitlessly trying to edit the Mint source code, I disabled <a href="http://code.google.com/speed/page-speed/docs/module.html"><code>mod_pagespeed</code></a> on the hunch that my code changes weren’t taking effect because <code>mod_pagespeed</code> was caching everything. All of a sudden, the Mint interface looked fine, and it turned out that my small tweaks didn’t really make much of a difference after all. I still haven’t figured out exactly why <code>mod_pagespeed</code> was causing issues, but disabling it sure did fix them. If anyone has any insight into this, please let me know.</p>

<h2 id="peppers">Peppers</h2>

<p>I mentioned that Mint is pluggable and extensible. In fact, that is its entire basis: every bit of functionality is provided by modular plugins called peppers. Mint comes with the default pepper that I mentioned before, but there are many more available. I use a number of them.</p>

<h3 id="backuprestorebackup"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/5/backup_restore/">Backup/Restore</a></h3>

<p>This pepper is self-explanatory: back up and restore your Mint stats. That’s it.</p>

<h3 id="iphoneiphone"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/57/iphone/">iPhone</a></h3>

<p>The default Mint interface isn’t that great for a smaller screen like the iPhone, so this pepper displays an optimized interface when you view Mint on an iPhone.</p>

<h3 id="outboundoutbound"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/60/outbound/">Outbound</a></h3>

<p>A lot of analytics apps try to show you where your visitors come from, and that information is important. You might be interested in where your visitors go next, so this pepper shows your most popular outbound links.</p>

<h3 id="user-agent-007user-agent"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/7/user_agent_007/">User Agent 007</a></h3>

<p>This cleverly-named pepper shows a breakdown of your visitors by user agent.</p>

<h3 id="real-estatereal-estate"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/9/real_estate/">Real Estate</a></h3>

<p>This one shows a breakdown of your visitors by the size of their screen.</p>

<h3 id="local-searcheslocal-search"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/6/local_searches/">Local Searches</a></h3>

<p>If your blogging software has a search mechanism, this pepper shows you what your visitors are searching for. Note that this is different than the search engine queries that bring visitors to your site that the default pepper shows. </p>

<h3 id="doorbelldoorbell"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/45/doorbell/">Doorbell</a></h3>

<p>When you’re viewing your Mint interface, the doorbell pepper provides a some audio feedback when you get a new visitor.</p>

<h3 id="errorserrors"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/92/errors/">Errors</a></h3>

<p>This pepper shows any error pages that your visitors may have seen, along with the page that was requested that caused that error.</p>

<h3 id="locationslocations"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/29/locations/">Locations</a></h3>

<p>This pepper provides a breakdown of your visitors by geographic location.</p>

<h3 id="sparkssparks"><a href="http://www.haveamint.com/peppermill/pepper/67/sparks/">Sparks!</a></h3>

<p>Sparklines provide a great way to view useful trends in a small space. This combined with the iPhone pepper makes checking visitor trends on the go a snap.</p>

<p>I use both Google analytics and Mint on my site, but I find myself looking at Mint much, much more often. It just offers a better view into the kind of people visiting your site, especially if you’re coming from a position of trying to understand what kind of content brings them to your site in the first place. Mint comes highly recommended.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Handle Pattern]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/03/the-handle-pattern/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-25T13:12:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/03/the-handle-pattern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m not entirely sure if there’s a better name for this pattern that already exists, but I like “handle pattern” to describe this method of keeping track of and managing “subscriptions”.</p>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
<span class="line-number">4</span>
<span class="line-number">5</span>
<span class="line-number">6</span>
<span class="line-number">7</span>
<span class="line-number">8</span>
<span class="line-number">9</span>
<span class="line-number">10</span>
<span class="line-number">11</span>
<span class="line-number">12</span>
<span class="line-number">13</span>
<span class="line-number">14</span>
<span class="line-number">15</span>
<span class="line-number">16</span>
<span class="line-number">17</span>
<span class="line-number">18</span>
<span class="line-number">19</span>
<span class="line-number">20</span>
<span class="line-number">21</span>
<span class="line-number">22</span>
<span class="line-number">23</span>
<span class="line-number">24</span>
<span class="line-number">25</span>
<span class="line-number">26</span>
<span class="line-number">27</span>
<span class="line-number">28</span>
<span class="line-number">29</span>
<span class="line-number">30</span>
<span class="line-number">31</span>
<span class="line-number">32</span>
<span class="line-number">33</span>
<span class="line-number">34</span>
<span class="line-number">35</span>
<span class="line-number">36</span>
<span class="line-number">37</span>
<span class="line-number">38</span>
<span class="line-number">39</span>
<span class="line-number">40</span>
<span class="line-number">41</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="javascript"><span class="line"><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">subscriber</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line">    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">_listeners</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">{};</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line">    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">s</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="c1">// Listen to a channel and call a callback when that channel fires</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="nx">listen</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">cb</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">            <span class="c1">// Add the callback to the list of listeners on the given channel</span>
</span><span class="line">            <span class="nx">_listeners</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">_listeners</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="p">[];</span>
</span><span class="line">            <span class="nx">_listeners</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">].</span><span class="nx">push</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">cb</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line">            <span class="k">return</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">                <span class="c1">// Return an object that can be used to remove the callback from the channel</span>
</span><span class="line">                <span class="nx">unlisten</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">                    <span class="c1">// Remove the callback from the list of listeners on that channel</span>
</span><span class="line">                    <span class="nx">_listeners</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">].</span><span class="nx">splice</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">_listeners</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">].</span><span class="nx">indexOf</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">cb</span><span class="p">),</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class="line">                <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class="line">            <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line">        <span class="c1">// Manually fire events on a given channel.</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="nx">publish</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">            <span class="nx">_listeners</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">_listeners</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="p">[];</span>
</span><span class="line">            <span class="nx">_listeners</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">].</span><span class="nx">forEach</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">cb</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">                <span class="nx">cb</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class="line">            <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line">    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">s</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="p">})();</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line"><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">h</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">subscriber</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">listen</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;update&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;The update event was fired!&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line"><span class="nx">subscriber</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">publish</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;update&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span> <span class="c1">// &gt; &quot;The update event was fired!&quot;</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line"><span class="nx">h</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">unlisten</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line"><span class="nx">subscriber</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">publish</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;update&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span> <span class="c1">// &gt; &lt;no output&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<p>When you have an event-driven application, like a Javascript app that performs actions based on user interaction or based on back end “pushes” to a listening front end, you often have a central “publisher” that handles firing events when certain actions occur. It makes sense to have a static <code>listen</code> function that takes a “channel” and a callback function to call when that channel gets updated. The problem comes when you have to decide how to <em>stop</em> listening to that channel. If you go with a static <code>unlisten</code> function on the publisher with the same signature as <code>listen</code> (the channel and callback), you need to keep track of which callback is listening to which channel, and it can get messy.</p>

<p>Instead, <code>listen</code> can return a <code>handle</code>, which is just an object that contains a method <code>unlisten</code> that knows exactly how to stop listening on the specific channel and with the specific callback that was given to <code>listen</code>. Then, the caller just needs to keep track of the return values of <code>listen</code> (as opposed to the <em>arguments</em> to <code>listen</code>) in order to be able to <code>unlisten</code> later.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://dojotoolkit.org/">Dojo</a> <a href="http://dojotoolkit.org/reference-guide/1.7/dojo/Stateful.html">Stateful</a> interface uses this pattern to watch values on objects. If you watch a property, a callback can be fired each time that property changes. The return value of <code>watch</code> is a handle that can be used to stop watching that particular property value.</p>

<p>Feel free to <a href="http://jsfiddle.net/tupton/nZKQz/">play around with this code on JSFiddle</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't Commit FIXME or TODO]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/02/dont-commit-fixme-or-todo/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-24T12:41:13-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/02/dont-commit-fixme-or-todo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
<span class="line-number">4</span>
<span class="line-number">5</span>
<span class="line-number">6</span>
<span class="line-number">7</span>
<span class="line-number">8</span>
<span class="line-number">9</span>
<span class="line-number">10</span>
<span class="line-number">11</span>
<span class="line-number">12</span>
<span class="line-number">13</span>
<span class="line-number">14</span>
<span class="line-number">15</span>
<span class="line-number">16</span>
<span class="line-number">17</span>
<span class="line-number">18</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="php"><span class="line"><span class="cp">&lt;?php</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">function</span> <span class="nf">getObject</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$id</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="nv">$object</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">null</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line">    <span class="c1">// TODO Do we need to validate username?</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="nv">$objects</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nv">$this</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">db</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">retrieveForUsername</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$this</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">username</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line">    <span class="c1">// FIXME Write `retrieveForIdAndUsername` instead of iterating here</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="k">foreach</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$objects</span> <span class="k">as</span> <span class="nv">$o</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$o</span><span class="o">-&gt;</span><span class="na">id</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="nv">$id</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class="line">            <span class="nv">$object</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nv">$o</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class="line">            <span class="k">break</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line">    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nv">$object</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<p>This shouldn’t happen. I’m not talking about the comically bad code – it’s a contrived example, but it proves the point – but about the little “notes” left by whoever committed this.</p>

<p>Do we need to validate the username? Probably. Find out, and take the necessary action. If you know your codebase well, it should take about ten seconds to know the answer.</p>

<p>The <code>FIXME</code> is a bit more time-consuming, but the payoff is greater. If you leave this <code>FIXME</code>, I’m going to assume one of two things: you’re a lazy programmer, or you’re a bad programmer. You’re lazy because you can’t be bothered to write something correctly or you’re bad because you don’t know <em>how</em> to write it correctly<sup id="fnref:bad-dev"><a href="#fn:bad-dev" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>Of course, use <code>TODO</code> or <code>FIXME</code> while you’re developing to keep a list of tasks that you have to finish before your feature is complete. Just don’t commit them to where other developers can see them and <em>certainly</em> don’t merge them to trunk.</p>

<p>If you’re lazy with that code now, there’s no way you’re going to overcome that laziness and come back to fix it later.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:bad-dev">
      <p>One could argue that being aware of bad code is better than nothing, but that’s fluffy. If you’re aware of a problem, you’re probably smart enough to do something about it.<a href="#fnref:bad-dev" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microwave Ovens Suck]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/02/microwave-ovens-suck/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-23T18:50:14-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/02/microwave-ovens-suck</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Really. My microwave helpfully makes the numbers 1 through 6 shortcuts for running for that number of minutes, on full power. When’s the last time you needed to microwave something for <em>six whole minutes</em>?</p>

<p>Most of my microwaving involves re-heating leftovers or softening things like tortillas or butter. These things don’t take minutes; they take <em>seconds</em>. And if I have something that really need to warm up over the course of one or two minutes, it certainly doesn’t need to be that long at full power. Those preset buttons are absolutely useless. I need presets for 10, 20, and 30 seconds, and maybe 90, and at power levels of 5, 7, and “hi”. Not “high”, mind you, “hi”.</p>

<p>The rest of my microwaving time is spent trying to defrost frozen meat, like a chicken breast or a tilapia filet. There’s a button for this, yes, but it requires that I guess the weight of the thing I’m defrosting. I don’t own a kitchen scale, but even if I did, I sure as hell wouldn’t bust it out to figure out how to long I need to defrost my meat. Let me tell you what I’m defrosting, and then figure out how long to defrost it. Defrosting is not a new science or even science at all.</p>

<p>Here’s another irksome feature: when I open the microwave door before the timer goes off, I really appreciate that it remembers how much time was left. Once eight hours have passed, though, I think it’s safe to assume that I’m no longer in need of that timer. “PRESS START” is not helpful after that long. Show me the clock again after a reasonable amount of time has passed.</p>

<p>Another thing: that awful beeping sound. I know some smug person with too much time on his hands has Googled his unit’s manual and has memorized the arcane sequence of button presses required to mute the microwave, but I haven’t. Why is there not just a mute button? It’s not for lack of room: put it under my “9 “ button or in between “Defrost” and “Popcorn” (which always burns those poor defenseless kernels) or even in the place of the “Reminder” button, because I don’t keep my todo list on my microwave.</p>

<p>Can someone “<a href="http://www.nest.com/">Nest</a>-ify” the microwave? I would buy one in a heartbeat.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Configuration]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/02/configuration/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-18T20:43:38-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/02/configuration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Starting a fresh environment on a new system isn’t a very common or regular task, but when you do, it comes in handy to have a quick and easy way to do it. To help with this, I keep my <code>vim</code> <a href="https://github.com/tupton/vim-support">environment</a> and my <a href="https://github.com/tupton/dotfiles">environment dot files</a> in version control on Github.</p>

<p>I use <a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen">Pathogen</a> to manage my <code>vim</code> plugins. I follow the examples in <a href="http://vimcasts.org/episodes/synchronizing-plugins-with-git-submodules-and-pathogen/">this great article on plugin management with Pathogen</a> to keep most of my plugins as <code>git</code> submodules. Installing my <code>vim</code> environment is just a matter of cloning the <code>git</code> repository and symlinking my <code>vimrc</code>.</p>

<p>I just spent some time cleaning up and organizing my dotfiles.  I wasn’t even using my old dotfiles repository on GitHub, but I quickly rectified that. I now keep my dotfiles in <code>~/.dotfiles</code> and symlink them to <code>~</code>. There is a helper script in my <a href="https://github.com/tupton/dotfiles">dotfiles repository</a> that sets up these symlinks.</p>

<p>Along with the usual <code>bashrc</code>, there are a few config files that aren’t as common. My <code>ackrc</code> defines a few convenient options and ignores directories with built artifacts in them. My (old) <code>pythonrc</code> defines a tab-completion function, although this might be outdated at this point. There’s a <code>tm_properties</code> config for <a href="http://blog.macromates.com/2011/textmate-2-0-alpha/">TextMate 2</a>.</p>

<p>Hopefully the fact that my configuration is out in the open will bring to light some useful features that I probably take for granted but you might not know about. So, go explore! Check out my <code>inputrc</code>, for example. I know that I discover new things almost every time I look at someone else’s <code>vimrc</code> or <code>bashrc</code>.</p>

<p>Do you have any configuration tips or tricks? Let me know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/coffee/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-07T14:37:42-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7164/6654753833_ab1c242b36_z_d.jpg" alt="Coffee" /></p>

<p>Like <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OTVE5iPMKLg">most of the world</a>, I love coffee. I usually drink a cup or two a day, and sometimes more. I’m lucky enough to live close to places that sell great coffee: Whole Foods roasts their own coffee, and there are numerous local places with great beans.</p>

<p>I usually make a full “batch” of coffee in a French press (or <em>сafetière</em>), but sometimes that’s too much. I know it’s considered blasphemous, but I got a Keurig single cup brewer for Christmas, and I absolutely love it. I was apprehensive about Keurig machines until I found out about refillable “K-Cups” that you could fill with your own, delicious coffee. I use the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000DLB2FI/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag;=thomupto-20&linkCode;=as2&camp;=1789&creative;=390957&creativeASIN;=B000DLB2FI">official Keurig “My K-Cup”</a>, but that requires that you replace the entire holster mechanism each time. It’s not time consuming, but it is a bit annoying.</p>

<p>I discovered the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/ekobrew-Refillable-Keurig-Brewers-1-Count/dp/B0051SU0OW/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&qid;=1325967276&sr;=8-1">Ekobrew</a>, which is a filter that fits in the existing cup holster. Two of them are on their way to my house from Amazon right now.</p>

<p>Regardless of how it gets there, coffee from the Keurig is (perhaps surprisingly) pleasant. It’s not the best cup of coffee, but it’s quick, easy, and clean.</p>

<p>I still use the French press when I need to make a bigger batch of coffee or if I want to relax and enjoy a really great cup. I use the seemingly-ubiquitous Bodum French press and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0043095WW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag;=thomupto-20&linkCode;=as2&camp;=1789&creative;=390957&creativeASIN;=B0043095WW">burr grinder</a> and keep the coffee warm in my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00004S56U/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag;=thomupto-20&linkCode;=as2&camp;=1789&creative;=390957&creativeASIN;=B00004S56U">Zojirushi carafe</a>. Coffee stays <em>hot</em> for hours on end, so I can make coffee in the morning and still enjoy it later in the afternoon. How I make coffee just depends on how much I need and what kind of mood I’m in.</p>

<p>One last thing: I also got a small stovetop espresso maker for Christmas, and it is amazing. When I want a treat, I make myself a café Americano: a bit of espresso in a normal-sized coffee cup and filled the rest of the way with hot water. Yum!</p>

<p><em>Full disclosure</em>: I’ve linked to a number of products on Amazon in this post, and most of them contain my affiliate link. I’ll get a small kickback if anything is bought via these links. I will only ever post links to products that I use and love, and that is certainly the case with everything here. I’m passionate about my coffee, and I don’t want to mislead anyone. I have not included my affiliate link to the Ekobrew refillable K-Cup because I have not received or used it at this time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Essential Tools]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/my-essential-tools/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T16:16:30-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/my-essential-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In light of some <a href="http://carpeaqua.com/2011/12/19/my-ultimate-developer-and-power-users-tool-list-for-mac-os-x-2011-edition-/">recent</a> <a href="http://collindonnell.com/blog/2012/1/4/essential-tools-2011.html">excellent</a> posts about tools that smart people use, here are my essential tools that I used in 2011.</p>

<h2 id="hardware">Hardware</h2>

<p>I use a 15” MacBook Pro i5 with 8 GB of RAM. It’s quick and does everything I need it to. It’s not <em>too</em> bulky, but it’s certainly bigger than my older 13” MacBook. I keep toying with the idea of a MacBook Air, but I can’t justify the cost and I don’t want to use two machines.</p>

<p>I connect to an Apple LED Cinema Display when I’m at my standing desk, and I use a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002MMY4WY/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag;=thomupto-20&linkCode;=as2&camp;=1789&creative;=390957&creativeASIN;=B002MMY4WY">Logitech wireless keyboard</a> and an Apple Magic Trackpad.</p>

<p>I do <a href="http://www.thomasupton.com/blog/2011/12/local-backups-are-great/">daily, local backups</a> to a smallish volume on a 1 TB hard drive. The rest of the drive holds my music, photos, and other media.</p>

<h2 id="software">Software</h2>

<p>I do all of my work (both professionally and on this site) on VMs in “the cloud” that I <code>ssh</code> to with <a href="http://www.iterm2.com/#/section/home">iTerm 2</a>. I love that it can copy-on-select and the customizable colors are more robust than in other terminal apps. I used the built in Terminal.app for a long time, but the latest iTerm 2 is stable and excellent.</p>

<p>I also use <a href="http://ditchnet.org/httpclient/">HTTP Client</a> to test our API, as well as both Firefox and Chrome.</p>

<p>When I write code, I usually use <a href="http://www.vim.org/"><code>vim</code></a>, but I’ve been testing out the recent alpha builds of <a href="http://blog.macromates.com/2011/textmate-2-0-alpha/">TextMate 2</a>.</p>

<p>When I write for this website or for my own personal notes, I’ve started using <a href="http://bywordapp.com/">Byword</a> to write and preview Markdown. Its fullscreen and “paragraph focus” modes are nice touches. I’ve heard good things about <a href="http://markedapp.com/">Marked</a>, which allows Markdown previews from any app, but I haven’t used it yet.</p>

<p>I’m not a huge calendar user, but I do keep track of <a href="http://www.last.fm/user/TUpton/events">shows I attend</a> and personal events on Google Calendar. I interact with my calendars with <a href="http://flexibits.com/fantastical">Fantastical</a>. Its natural language event input is pretty great and lets me add events really quickly.</p>

<p>I work on and use a browser-based email client at work, but I also like to use <a href="http://sparrowmailapp.com/">Sparrow</a>. The minimal interface stays out of the way, but all my mail is available quickly. Shortcuts for reply and reply all make it easy to respond to threads. A nice little touch: Sparrow automatically picked up the fact that I had an IMAP folder called Archive in my work email and started using it when I press Delete to archive messages.</p>

<p>I use <a href="http://www.alfredapp.com/">Alfred</a> all day every day. My usage statistics say I average 13.6 uses per day, but if you didn’t count weekends, holidays, or days that I don’t actually use my computer, I bet it’d be a lot higher. I <em>love</em> the clipboard management.</p>

<p>I occasionally use <a href="http://getcloudapp.com/">Cloud</a> to quickly upload screenshots, but I don’t use it for much else.</p>

<p>I use <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/">Dropbox</a> to manage files, share some music with friends, and back up certain documents. I also store my (encrypted) <a href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword">1Password</a> data on Dropbox so that I can access my passwords from anywhere.</p>

<p><a href="http://mizage.com/#macdivvy">Divvy</a> and <a href="http://cordlessdog.com/stay/">Stay</a> are two window management tools that I use all the time. When I disconnect from my display, Stay puts my windows back to where I want them. It doesn’t quite work with Chrome, but everything else works well. Divvy lets me resize windows on a custom-sized grid. You can even define shortcuts – I use “c” for a centered window and “6” for a window taking up 60% of the right side of the screen.</p>

<p>I recently started using <a href="http://www.evernote.com/">Evernote</a>, but I haven’t gotten into it just yet. I’ll have more to write about that when learn how to use it and actually start using it more. I do use <a href="http://www.evernote.com/about/download/clearly.php">Evernote’s Clearly</a> browser extension to read articles on line.</p>

<p>For my musical pleasure throughout the day, I still use iTunes a lot of the time. However, <a href="http://www.rdio.com/">Rdio</a> (with <a href="http://www.rogueamoeba.com/airfoil/">Airfoil</a>) is usually how I listen to music these days. Airfoil makes it easy to listen to music in my living room via my Apple TV.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uptonian Thoughts on Twitter]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/uptonian-thoughts-on-twitter/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-04T22:50:51-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/uptonian-thoughts-on-twitter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now follow <a href="http://twitter.com/uptonin">Uptonian Thoughts on Twitter</a>! I’m using the <a href="http://somadesign.ca/2011/lessn-shortlinks-wordpress-plugin/">Lessn Shortlinks</a> and <a href="http://ottopress.com/wordpress-plugins/simple-twitter-connect/">Simple Twitter Connect</a> Wordpress plugins to tweet my posts to @uptonin.</p>

<p>I might still occasionally link to my own posts on my @thomasupton account, but all posts and articles, along with information about the site, will be available on @uptonin.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lessn]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/lessn/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-04T22:37:07-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/lessn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently installed <a href="http://shauninman.com/archive/2009/08/17/less_n">Lessn</a> and then <a href="http://lessnmore.net/">Lessn More</a> to take control of my own short links. Lessn is a very simple URL shortener that is hosted on my own domain.</p>

<p>I registered <a href="http://upton.in/">upton.in</a> to serve my short links. I chose the “.in” TLD because it’s short and common. I do wish there was an “.on” TLD so I could register <em>upt.on</em>, but I like the connotation of “in”. As <a href="https://twitter.com/thomasupton/status/154218836722335745">I said on Twitter the other day</a>, it can mean “Internet, inside, come in, infinity, interesting” among other things. </p>

<p>Lessn also integrates nicely with <a href="http://haveamint.com/">Mint</a>, which I recently started using. I plan to write more on that shortly.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unplayed]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/unplayed/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-02T19:23:21-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/unplayed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Santa brought me <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002BSC54I/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&tag;=thomupto-20&linkCode;=as2&camp;=1789&creative;=9325&creativeASIN;=B002BSC54I">The Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword</a> for Christmas (thanks Mom!). I’ve enjoyed playing it, just as I’ve enjoyed playing video games for nearly my entire life.</p>

<p>In recent years, however, I’ve abandoned or not fully played all of my video games. I attempted to maintain a Google Docs spreadsheet to keep track of my unplayed games, but it quickly became more neglected than the games themselves.</p>

<p>I recently found out about Shaun Inman’s <a href="http://www.shauninman.com/archive/2011/04/18/unplayed"><em>Unplayed</em></a>, and it seemed perfect. It’s like a much simpler, lightweight Shelfari for video games. You can now see which games I’m playing (or not playing) at my <a href="http://www.thomasupton.com/unplayed/"><em>Unplayed</em> page</a>. For now, I’m going back to Skyloft!</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Christopher Nolan's "Other" Movies]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/christopher-nolans-other-movies/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T21:33:42-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2012/01/christopher-nolans-other-movies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first Christopher Nolan movie I saw was the incredible <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0209144/"><em>Memento</em></a>. I’ve watched it many times since, and I always manage to catch something new. It’s a great movie the first and tenth time you watch it. It’s well-written – with some help from his brother Jonathan, who has helped out on other films since – and the attention to detail is incredible. </p>

<p>I think Nolan caught the attention of most of the movie-going public for his reboot of the Batman franchise. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0372784/"><em>Batman Begins</em></a> is one of the best comic book translations, outdone only by its sequel, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0468569/"><em>The Dark Knight</em></a>. Nolan wisely decided to take breaks between Batman films to make other films that he was interested in. He managed to pull this off because of his own production company, Syncopy Films, and his success as a director. As a result we’ve got two great films so far: <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0482571/"><em>The Prestige</em></a> and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1375666/"><em>Inception</em></a>.</p>

<p>I love that Nolan has focused on other projects that he’s passionate about to avoid creating anything “stale” or boring. I think there’s a larger lesson there that most people can take away. Sometimes you can make something better by <em>not</em> giving it attention.</p>

<p>If Nolan’s “interstitial” movies keep improving at the same rate, we’re in for a treat in 2014.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/writing/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-25T23:19:21-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently started using <a href="http://bywordapp.com/">Byword</a> on OS X and <a href="http://www.secondgearsoftware.com/elements/">Elements</a> on iOS for my writing in general. Both apps are <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a> editors that, in conjunction with Dropbox, let me write from nearly anywhere.</p>

<p>I write my blog posts in Markdown, but the format is useful for almost any kind of writing. Any application that can read plain text can read Markdown for those times that you need to keep it simple, or you can convert to HTML for when you want or need to make it a bit more presentable.</p>

<p>I love using Byword in its fullscreen and paragraph focus view. It’s a great way to minimize distractions with enough context to let you properly proofread your writing. The Markdown to HTML preview is a keyboard shortcut away, and saving to a folder in Dropbox means that I can access my files anywhere.</p>

<p>Elements requires a Dropbox account to work, so I specified the same folder that I save documents from Byword into. Et voilà, I can edit or add to a blog post or any other writing on my iPhone or iPad. Elements has a great Markdown preview, too, and it’s distraction-free (from other apps) by nature of being an iOS app.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local Backups are Great]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/local-backups-are-great/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-23T21:48:47-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/local-backups-are-great</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I use <a href="http://www.shirt-pocket.com/SuperDuper/SuperDuperDescription.html">SuperDuper!</a> to make daily backups to my local hard drive. <a href="http://www.thomasupton.com/blog/2010/12/automated-backups-with-tarsnap/">Remote backup</a> is important, but it’s always nice to have an easily-accessible way to recover from a hard drive disaster, especially when you need to fix the situation <em>quickly</em>.</p>

<h2 id="your-backup-device">Your Backup Device</h2>

<p>Choosing the right hard drive to use for your local backup isn’t a difficult choice, but it is an important one.  Sometimes you can find great deals on good brands (Western Digital or Seagate, to name a couple brands that I have used and liked) on <a href="http://www.newegg.com/">Newegg</a>. The requirements for a hard drive really depend on how you want to use it.</p>

<p>If you want a hard drive dedicated to backup, any drive with a relatively quick speed (I would go with 7200 RPM or higher) and a size that’s at least a bit bigger than the drive you’re backing up will be a great option.</p>

<p>If you want to use a hard drive for other things – to store your media or back up another drive – you’ll obviously need something bigger. I have a 1 TB drive that I have split into two volumes. One volume is a bit bigger than my MacBook Pro’s hard drive (128 GB)  and I use it to hold my backups; the other takes up the rest of the space and is used to store all of my music, movies, and photos.</p>

<p>Solid state drives are another option, but I’ve found that the extra cost isn’t worth the speed benefits. I would absolutely recommend a solid state drive to use in your main computer on a daily basis – I have a 128 GB solid state drive in my MacBook Pro and it’s noticeably faster than the mechanical hard drives I’ve used in MacBooks past. However, when it comes to something like backups, where you’re mostly writing to it in a situation that isn’t time-sensitive (e.g. at night), I think mechanical drives are the best option because you can get much more storage space for much less money.</p>

<h2 id="software-that-helps-you">Software That Helps You</h2>

<p>I mentioned earlier that I use SuperDuper!, but there are many other backup applications out there. Some of them may fit your specific needs better. The key feature is to have an automated and <em>bootable</em> copy of your hard drive ready to go at a moment’s notice.</p>

<p>I admittedly have not given Time Machine a fair shot, but that’s because I don’t have a use case for its main draw. “Going back in time” to an earlier version of a file is not something I need to do on a regular basis. And now with Lion’s Versions feature, I don’t need a whole backup just to keep recent versions of my files around.</p>

<p>Another option is <a href="http://www.bombich.com/ccc_features.html">Carbon Copy Cloner</a>. It makes bootable backups and can be scheduled to back up on a daily basis. It’s free to try; donations are requested if you continue to use the product.</p>

<p>I love SuperDuper! because it’s so simple. The interface tells you in plain English what is going to happen. I set up my nightly backups one time a couple years ago and the only time I ever see the app again is when I am traveling without my hard drive. When a backup fails, the application stays open to tell you what went wrong. That rarely happens though: usually an incremental backup occurs at 3am that takes less than ten minutes to complete. When it’s done, my data is safe and sound in two places.</p>

<p>The successful backups are bootable, meaning that you can just choose the backup volume as the boot volume when you <a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1310">hold Option after you turn your computer on</a> and restore from there. If you just want to restore certain files instead of everything, the drive is right there in Finder for you to navigate as usual.</p>

<h2 id="backup-is-not-a-daunting-task">Backup Is Not a Daunting Task</h2>

<p>Almost none of my “non-technical” friends (i.e. friends who do other things in their lives besides fiddle with computers) back up their computers. And yet I know that each one of those friends would be devastated if their hard drive crashed and they lost their music or photos. Local backups are the simplest way to avoid this, and it’s so simple to set up:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Buy a hard drive (7200 RPM and at least as big as the drive you want to back up) and <a href="http://www.iclarified.com/entry/index.php?enid=1075">format it using OS X’s built-in Disk Utility</a>.</li>
  <li>Set up a <a href="http://www.shirt-pocket.com/SuperDuper/SuperDuperDescription.html">backup application</a> to do daily backups of your entire disk.</li>
</ul>

<p>That’s it. Back up your data. It’s so simple and so useful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Move Your Domains Away From GoDaddy]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/move-your-domains-away-from-godaddy/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-23T09:06:34-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/move-your-domains-away-from-godaddy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Stop Online Piracy Act (explanation via <a href="http://kottke.org/11/12/the-internets-go-daddy-issues">Kottke</a> on <a href="[http://www.techdirt.com/articles/20111122/04254316872/definitive-post-why-sopa-protect-ip-are-bad-bad-ideas.shtml]">what’s wrong with SOPA</a>) is bad for the internet in general. <a href="http://www.thedomains.com/2011/11/15/here-is-godaddys-statement-in-support-of-the-stop-online-privacy-act-house-hearing-tomorrow/">GoDaddy supports SOPA</a>, and this has alarmed many of its customers, including this <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/nmnie/godaddy_supports_sopa_im_transferring_51_domains/">Redditor with fifty one domains</a> and myself.</p>

<p>Again via Kottke, I came across <a href="http://blog.jeffepstein.me/post/14629857835/a-step-by-step-guide-to-transfer-domains-out-of-godaddy">this guide to moving from GoDaddy to NameCheap</a> (<a href="http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:1BOfAgmNnuAJ:blog.jeffepstein.me/post/14629857835/a-step-by-step-guide-to-transfer-domains-out-of-godaddy+&cd;=1&hl;=en&ct;=clnk&gl;=us">Google cache</a>). <a href="https://www.namecheap.com">NameCheap</a> has officially come out against SOPA, and their site and experience has been nothing but top notch since I started the transfer process.</p>

<p>I’ve also heard good things about <a href="https://www.hover.com/">Hover</a>; by all means shop around for a registrar that fits your needs and doesn’t blatantly support SOPA.</p>

<p>My transfer process to NameCheap is nearly complete, and I couldn’t be happier to leave GoDaddy. Don’t forget that December 29th is Move Your Domain Day!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Favorite Albums of 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/my-ten-favorite-albums-of-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-21T09:31:58-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/my-ten-favorite-albums-of-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="a-musical-year">A Musical Year</h2>

<p>Music has been a huge part of my life for a long time now. I started playing the violin in the fourth grade. I played the saxophone for six years, including for four years in my high school marching band. I played in a punk rock band with my best friends from high school for four years. The next and latest chapter of my musical life began when I moved to Austin, TX in June of 2010.</p>

<p>They call Austin the “Live Music Capital of the World”. To many, that sounds like exaggeration and a desperate grasp at something to be proud of. To those who have experienced it, it is almost an understatement. Whether you’ve been punched in the gut in the pit at Emo’s or just seen that gnarly rocker chick band Guilty Pleasures while walking past Thirsty Nickel on a Saturday night, there’s no denying that music is in the blood of Austin. I love it.</p>

<p>2011 was a musical year for me. According to <a href="http://www.last.fm/user/TUpton/events/2011">Last.fm</a>, I went to 46 musical events, including SXSW, ACL, and FFFFest. And that doesn’t count the numerous times I caught local acts on the weekends. Some might have thought of 2011 as a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=10100626303464693&id;=6206637">lackluster</a> year for music, but I disagree. There were some fantastic releases by some great bands; old favorites thanked their fans with fresh material and new (but sometimes only new to me) acts dug their way into my ears and heart.</p>

<h3 id="a-new-medium">A New Medium</h3>

<p>There is something else that affected my music listening habits in 2011: <a href="http://www.rdio.com/">Rdio</a>. I signed up in July and immediately started listening to tons of new music. In November, I listened to at least one new album each day as part of Month of New Music (see my <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/thomasupton/status/142345008454959105">#monm playlist</a>.) Rdio tore down any remaining barriers that hindered listening to any music, anywhere, quickly. I chose Rdio over <a href="http://www.spotify.com/us/">Spotify</a> for a few reasons: Rdio has better social features, better recommendations, a similarly-sized catalogue, better apps on both the desktop and mobile, and a better blog filled with interviews with musicians, reviews, and recommendations.</p>

<p>According to iTunes, I have seventy one albums that were released in 2011. This is lower than any other year that I have been adding music to iTunes, but that is explained by my prolific use of Rdio. I have purchased a few albums after streaming them, but Rdio is almost like having a second library. I briefly looked for statistics on Rdio listening habits, but I couldn’t find any. Believe me when I say I listen to a ton of music every day while working.</p>

<p>I made a list of nineteen albums that were my favorites of the year. I’ve pared it down to ten that I want to talk about, but I’ll mention the others at the end. All in all, it was a great year of music for me.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="running-from-a-gamble-by-company-of-thieves">Running From a Gamble by Company of Thieves</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/company-of-thieves-running-from-a-gamble.jpg" alt="Running From a Gamble by Company of Thieves" /></p>

<p>Genevieve Schatz can sing. She has a huge voice, especially for such a small, unassuming person. She’s backed by a band that can simultaneously rock out and complement her vocals. This is a poppy album, but it’s filled with soul <em>and</em> rock. The first song I heard from <a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJUCYo"><em>Running from a Gamble</em></a> was the incredible “Death of Communication.” From a simple beginning, it quickly builds into a spunky anthem. The outro to that song leaves you wanting more, and more is what you get on <em>Gamble</em>. Every song has character, with lots of soul and even blues influences. See this band live and stand in awe.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="barton-hollow-by-the-civil-wars">Barton Hollow by The Civil Wars</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/the-civil-wars-barton-hollow.jpg" alt="Barton Hollow by The Civil Wars" /></p>

<p>If you had asked me five years ago if I would ever pick a folk or country-influenced album to put on my list of favorites from the past year, I would have laughed. Then I heard <a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJRNEE"><em>Barton Hollow</em></a>.</p>

<p>This is a bit of a silly and meaningless (to everyone but me) story, but I’ll recount it anyway. I was at a friend’s house for a party over the summer. I had traveled halfway across the country to go, so I was staying over and was the only one left the next day. I have a tradition to trade music with this friend whenever we meet up, so he gave me a number of albums and told me to check one or two of them out while he went to take care of some errands. I just picked <em>Barton Hollow</em> by chance. I put it on and laid down on the bed and just stared at the ceiling and listened to the entire album. It’s so calming and soothing, and it was perfect for that moment.</p>

<p>I’ve since listened to this album many times. Both members of this band can sing incredibly well, and their song-writing and story-telling skills are second to none. The vocals are certainly the focal point of The Civil Wars’ music, but the guitar picking and occasional percussion are nothing to scoff at. This is beautiful music.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="the-king-of-limbs-by-radiohead">The King of Limbs by Radiohead</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/radiohead-the-king-of-limbs.jpg" alt="The King of Limbs by Radiohead" /></p>

<p>I’ll never understand why <a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJSzO0"><em>The King of Limbs</em></a> was poorly received by both critics and fans alike. I tend not to compare Radiohead releases to each other — <em>Kid A</em> is one of my favorite albums, but it doesn’t mean I like it any <em>better</em> than <em>OK Computer</em> or <em>Hail to the Thief</em>, it just means that I enjoy it for what it is and how it makes me feel in comparison to other albums that are not made my crazy Englishmen.</p>

<p>Radiohead is definitely a band all about feel. <em>Limbs</em> seems to have more of an electronic feel to it. There are little “glitches” on the tracks, the percussion is so precise that it’s almost robotic, and synths are prevalent. Radiohead has always had hints of this kind of thing since early on, but it’s out in the open here.</p>

<p>The band released a set of remixes of the album throughout the year, and they actually serve to show how great the album is: each one of these songs can and is interpreted in a number of ways.</p>

<p>I love the muted guitar on “Morning Mr Magpie” and the haunting lyrics of the aptly-named “Give Up The Ghost”. If nothing else, <em>Limbs</em> has made me look forward to where Radiohead takes us next. </p>

<hr />

<h2 id="weightless-by-animals-as-leaders">Weightless by Animals as Leaders</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/animals-as-leaders-weightless.jpg" alt="Weightless by Animals as Leaders" /></p>

<p>Two eight-string guitarists and one insane drummer — it’s such an unusual lineup, and Animals as Leaders is an unusual band. Started as a bit of a side or solo project by lead guitarist Tosin Abasi, his debut album featured just one man and programmed drums, but it laid the groundwork for a technical metal act like no other. After recruiting some bandmates, Animals went on tour and proceeded to melt the faces of anyone who got close.</p>

<p><a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJQT-Y"><em>Weightless</em></a> takes the concepts explored on the debut — polyrhythms, syncopated percussion, quickly sweeping arpeggios — and multiplies everything by ten. Thousand. It’s heavier, more chaotic, and tighter than ever.</p>

<p>This is another band to see live. They somehow still have stage presence despite the lack of a proper frontman and vocals, and Abasi seems to take genuine pleasure in blowing minds with his music. Percussionist Navene Koperweis manages to keep up with both the twisted programmed beats of old and with his own work on <em>Weightless</em>. It is certainly a feat to play something that someone else wrote with a computer; it’s something else entirely to continue to write new material in the same style.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="burst-apart-by-the-antlers">Burst Apart by The Antlers</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/the-antlers-burst-apart.jpg" alt="Burst Apart by The Antlers" /></p>

<p>My immediate reaction to “I Don’t Want Love” was “this is a lighter direction for The Antlers than <em>Hospice</em>.” Peter Silberman’s lyrics weren’t much (or even any) happier, but the music was lighter, more melodic, and a little poppier. There’s more rock influence throughout this record than on <em>Hospice.</em> In fact, there’s more, period. Every song is meatier. While some may say that the sparseness of <em>Hospice</em> was one of its key elements, the full-bodied, well-crafted songs of <a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJUYlE"><em>Burst Apart</em></a> are even more essential to bringing The Antlers to life.</p>

<p>The main contributors to this full sound are Michael Lerner’s focused percussion and the addition of layered guitar work, provided live by Timothy Mislock. The riffs in Parentheses are a definite stand-out. Both on the stage and in the studio, one can see the passion behind the music. I’ve been lucky enough to catch The Antlers live a number of times, and each show is better than the last, with more energy than they could capture on the record. I’ve seen them on the intimate Parish stage, and I’ve seen them on the giant AMD stage at ACL. No matter the setting, these guys play their hearts out.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="father-son-holy-ghost-by-girls">Father, Son, Holy Ghost by Girls</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/girls-father-son-holy-ghost.jpg" alt="Father, Son, Holy Ghost by Girls" /></p>

<p>Once <a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJRUZQ"><em>Father, Son, Holy Ghost</em></a> gets going (which is right away), Girls start rocking. There’s a bit of Spoon influence on the opening track, and a bit of Wilco throughout, but Girls manage to carve out their own rock niche here. “Die” really puts the pedal to the metal, and crowd-favorite “Vomit” has an incredibly catchy melody.</p>

<p>I admittedly know very little about Girls. I saw that they were recommended to me on Rdio, and I couldn’t stop listening to the album. I saw them live at Fun Fun Fun Fest, and they were amazing, but the record is where they really shine. It’s the sort of rock that doesn’t really stand out from the crowd too much until you realize that you’ve stopped doing whatever else it was you were doing while listening and your undivided attention is given to the music.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="little-hell-by-city-and-colour">Little Hell by City and Colour</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/city-and-colour-little-hell.jpg" alt="Little Hell by City and Colour" /></p>

<p>With the addition of percussion and backup guitars to nearly every song, Dallas Green has fleshed out his solo project to a full-fledged folk act. His lyrics are still tragic and romantic, but now they have more meat behind them.</p>

<p>I must have listened to <em>Bring Me Your Love</em> two hundred times. I haven’t listened to <a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJUrgI"><em>Little Hell</em></a> that much just yet, but I know I will. I can’t exactly pinpoint why, but this music is inherently re-playable. It never gets old. I usually chalk it up to Green’s incredible story-telling ability and pleasant accompaniment, but no matter how you try to explain it, this is great stuff.</p>

<p>Prepare to be saddened, but also prepare to leave what you’re doing and enter Green’s lyrical world.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="no-devolucin-by-thursday">No Devolución by Thursday</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/thursday-no-devolucion.jpg" alt="No Devolución by Thursday" title="No Devolución" /></p>

<p>Thursday turned a furious corner with 2006’s <em>A City by the Light Divided</em> and hasn’t looked back. <a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJV4mU"><em>No Devolución</em></a> is the ultimate manifestation of the post rock-influenced dynamic that was only hinted at on their previous two efforts. There is an almost monstrous quality to some of the tracks on <em>No Devolución</em>: “Past and Future Ruins” is chaotic and grandiose all at once. The percussion through the entire album is forceful: the drums drive and the bass pulses. Ghastly yells are next to quiet, almost croaked vocals.</p>

<p>Geoff Rickly’s lyrics have always been somewhat enigmatic, and that is no different here. There are moments of poignancy — “I lost my wedding ring / down the kitchen sink” — but there are still some puzzlers — “There’s a thousand black cars / driving around in my blood stream.”</p>

<p><em>No Devolución</em> is Thursday’s magnum opus in a literal sense of the phrase. It is great, and it is the sum of all the passion that these guys have for music; a true work of the heart. It is sad that Thursday has <a href="http://thursday.net/thank-you">decided step down off of the stage</a>, but we can all be thankful for what they left us with.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="garden-window-by-obrother">Garden Window by O’Brother</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/garden-window-o-brother.jpg" alt="Garden Window by O'Brother" /></p>

<p>Huge. Everything about Garden Window is full, monolithic, and <em>epic</em>. I first heard O’Brother live in August at Emo’s inside. Even there on that puny stage, they had a wall-of-sound presence that couldn’t be ignored. I saw them a couple of months later at the new Emo’s East, and they were even tighter and bigger sounding. Needless to say, I was excited about the release of their LP, <a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJP-oU"><em>Garden Window</em></a>.</p>

<p>Every song on the album is meaningful — there is no filler. There are some lengthy songs here — crowd favorite “Poison!” clocks in at nearly eight minutes, and “Cleanse Me” is fourteen minutes long — but <em>Garden Window</em> never drags. Quite the opposite: each song is filled with so much building tension and dynamic that it feels like you’re going to explode with each listen. It’s hard to put O’Brother into a single category or genre, but it’s very heavy at its heaviest and it’s always unrelenting. This is post-rock for those who like their coffee strong and black.</p>

<p>I highly recommend seeing O’Brother live, in case that wasn’t obvious. They do a great job of capturing their sound on record, but it’s one thing to rock out to <em>Garden Window</em> with your headphones on at your desk and another thing entirely to hear the bass drone through a song with a cello bow while eye-bulging screams are heard over a wall of guitars and drums.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="majorminor-by-thrice">Major/Minor by Thrice</h2>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/images/album/2011/thrice-major-minor.jpg" alt="Major/Minor by Thrice" /></p>

<p>Thrice has delivered great musical experiences for over ten years. They have taken a curvy road to the release of <a href="http://rd.io/x/QVhGxyJQWhk"><em>Major/Minor</em></a>, but it’s been an enjoyable journey every step of the way.</p>

<p><em>Major/Minor</em> is the most natural and expected follow-up to any album in Thrice’s discography. It builds on <em>Beggars’</em> grooviness but adds a lot more punch and poignancy. Every riff is carefully crafted, every beat brings you into the song. Every song is killer.</p>

<p>Thrice could not have <a href="http://www.thrice.net/post/13115093663/an-announcement-from-dustin">ended their musical career</a> on a higher note. The band could never put out any material that disappointed me, but I think this surpasses even harsh critics’ expectations. Let’s face it though: who’s a harsh critic of Thrice?</p>

<p>The first song I heard was the lead single and album opener, “Yellow Belly”. Its bluesy riff motif is echoed throughout the track, and right from the get-go we can feel that this is Thrice at their best. Other standout tracks include “Call It In The Air”, “Words In The Water”, and “Disarmed”, but there isn’t any filler here.</p>

<p>I was heartbroken to hear that Thrice was taking a break shortly after ending the tour that supported the release of <em>Major/Minor</em>. Thankfully I was able to see them live one last time. I know that every member of the band reached that decision after much contention. I’ve heard rumors that brothers Riley and Ed Breckenridge are working on something together, Dustin Kensrue remains the music worship leader at his church in Orange County, and I know that Teppei Teranishi cannot stay away from making music from long. I’m interested in hearing the direction that each of these guys go after being part of such a great band for so long.</p>

<hr />

<p>Like I said earlier, I picked out nineteen total albums this year. Here are the “honorable mentions,” so to speak, with a little bit about what I loved about them.</p>

<h4 id="mastodon---the-hunter">Mastodon - The Hunter</h4>

<p>Less “out-there” than <em>Crack the Skye</em>, it has some of the most poppy songs Mastodon has ever written, but all the face-melting is still there.</p>

<h4 id="man-man---life-fantastic">Man Man - Life Fantastic</h4>

<p>Incredible live act; the song writing just keeps getting better (and more sincere).</p>

<h4 id="neon-indian---era-extraa">Neon Indian - Era Extraña</h4>

<p>I only just found out about this band. It’s great music for chilling out or working to.</p>

<h4 id="fleet-foxes---helplessness-blues">Fleet Foxes - Helplessness Blues</h4>

<p>Vocal heaven. There are so many instruments and layers going on here. This is gorgeous, sleepy music.</p>

<h4 id="mister-heavenly---out-of-love">Mister Heavenly - Out of Love</h4>

<p>“Doom wop” is such a hilariously accurate term, and I can’t wait to hear more from these guys if they keep it going.</p>

<h4 id="august-burns-red---leveler">August Burns Red - Leveler</h4>

<p>These guys keep getting better and better. I don’t know how, but they outdid <em>Constellations</em> here. “Internal Cannon” is a standout track with its salsa breakdown — that’s not a typo.</p>

<h4 id="florence--the-machine---ceremonials">Florence + The Machine - Ceremonials</h4>

<p>A lot more serious this time around, but more heart and passion. I’d love to see this act live.</p>

<h4 id="childish-gambino---camp">Childish Gambino - Camp</h4>

<p>A lot of people dismiss Donald Glover as another actor-wannabe-rapper, but he’s got the chops. So many great beats and awesome, meaningful lyrics here.</p>

<h4 id="cloudkicker---let-yourself-be-huge">Cloudkicker - Let Yourself Be Huge</h4>

<p>It took a lot for me not to include this on my list of ten favorites. The closing track is amazing. The whole album is such a departure from other Cloudkicker material, and I’m curious to see where it goes next. Highly recommended.</p>

<hr />

<p>A lot of my picks centered around bands that I have also seen live this year. There’s something visceral about watching a band make music right in front of you. Whether you’re hearing a new act live for the first time or you’re enjoying live renditions of some of your old favorites, there’s something to be said for experiencing that beauty up close and personal.</p>

<p>I hope you enjoyed my picks. Please let me know what you think and what your favorite music of 2011 is.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[And Now For Something Completely Similar]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/and-now-for-something-completely-similar/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T00:03:48-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2011/12/and-now-for-something-completely-similar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi there. Remember me? It’s been a while, I know. Sorry I have not kept in touch. While I would be lying if I promised that I would never go silent for that long again, I have, for mulitple reasons, renewed my interest in writing.</p>

<p>I do not have many topics lined up, but I have the desire to write. Stay tuned for a bit of a year-end cliché and we’ll take it from there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
