<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Websites | Uptonian Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/categories/websites/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tupton.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-19T00:01:59-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://tupton.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Upton]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Stats]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2008/03/twitter-stats/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-30T00:12:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2008/03/twitter-stats</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Update:</strong> <a href="http://www.tweetstats.com/">TweetStats</a> webifies a version of these Twitter statistics.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2008/03/twitter_stats-300x154.png" alt="Twitter stats, by hour." /></p>

<p>Damon Cortesi wrote a <a href="http://dcortesi.com/2007/12/27/twitter-stats/">pretty nifty script to grab some Twitter statistics</a>. A bunch of people modified his script in order to <a href="http://bradkellett.com/twitter_stats.html">webify it</a>, <a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp/2008/01/02/twitter-stats-in-svg-using-gnuplot/">plot the results using gnuplot</a>, and <a href="http://iamthewalr.us/blog/2008/01/02/twitter-stats/">plot the results with the Google Charts API</a>.</p>

<p>This last modification really intrigued me, as I know there are <a href="http://google-code-updates.blogspot.com/2008/01/chartmaker-tool-for-google-chart-api.html">a few wrappers for the Google Charts API</a> available, including one for Python. I decided to modify <a href="http://iamthewalr.us/blog/2008/01/02/twitter-stats/">Colin Barrett’s Python script</a> that uses the Google Charts API to use the <a href="http://pygooglechart.slowchop.com/">pygooglechart</a> module.</p>

<p>So now instead of:</p>

<pre><code>if f[0] == "\n":
    s = "http://chart.apis.google.com/chart?cht=bvg&amp;chbh;=15&amp;chs;=600x300&amp;chd;=t:%s&amp;chxt;=y,x&amp;
    chxr=0,0,%d&amp;chtt;=%s"
    s = s % ( str(map(lambda x: x*100/max(v), v)).replace(" ", "")[1:-1], max(v), t )
</code></pre>

<p>we have:</p>

<pre><code># If we are at a newline, we have just finished gathering data for a single chart
if fields[0] == "\n":
    # Most of the time we are generating a vertical bar chart
    chart = GroupedVerticalBarChart(600, 300)
    # Set the y-axis range according to the current data
    chart.set_axis_range(Axis.LEFT, 0, max(chartData))
</code></pre>

<p>I also commented my modifications because I’m still on winter break and I felt like it.</p>

<p>You can <a href="http://www.thomasupton.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2008/01/pygooglechart_twitter_stats.zip">download my modified script here</a>. Make sure you have the pygooglechart module and read the included README.txt file.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peel OS X Music Blog Player & Reader]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2007/04/peel-os-x-music-blog-client/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-09T01:10:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2007/04/peel-os-x-music-blog-client</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thomasupton.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2007/04/snipshot_d4qr5b2m6gw.png" alt="Peel for OS X" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.getpeel.com/">Peel for OS X</a> is a beta music blog client that aggregates mp3 files from user-specified music blogs, and allows you to view the music blog right there in the app.  While it is great software, using it for one day has made me realize that a lot of potentially deal-breaking features are missing from this piece of software.  Thankfully, this is the reason public betas were invented, and, without further ado and in no particular order whatsoever, here is my wish-list for Peel:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Better Flagged Songs Management</p>

    <p>I want a central location (separate window, source list, whatever) for all the songs that I have flagged.  Sometimes I don’t have time or I don’t want to download a song, but I’d like to flag it in order to deal with it later.  I need to be able to see all flagged songs, regardless of the music blog from which they originally came.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Downloads Window</p>

    <p>A window would be much easier to manage and visualize than those small progress bars that are currently in place.  Additionally, it would be nice if there was a way to scan the download directory to see if the downloaded songs are still there.  The check mark that appears next to a downloaded song will always remain present, even when the downloaded song has been removed from the hard drive.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Search</p>

    <p>Let me search for artists, songs, music blogs (on the web, not search for local files), and, while we’re at it, make adding blogs easier.  Get website titles automatically, and don’t make me enter a title just to add a new music blog.  Handle feed URLs as well as music site URLs, too.  Peel crashed while adding a Wordpress RSS feed to the source list.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Better iTunes Integration</p>

    <p><em>Please</em> let me add Peel songs to a specific playlist.  I don’t want these singles mucking up my pristine album-only music library.  I spent way too much time tagging my music library to have it littered with improperly tagged music.  If you give me the option to add to a playlist, I can reduce this mess a lot more efficiently.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Better Playback Controls</p>

    <p>Allow me to shuffle songs, both within individual blogs and globally.  Make the spacebar a play/pause  button, and reflect that in the Controls menu.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><a href="http://www.last.fm/">Last.fm</a> support would be awesome, too.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[del.icio.us Links]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2007/03/delicious-links/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-18T20:45:57-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2007/03/delicious-links</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have added a <a href="http://del.icio.us/">del.icio.us</a> “<a href="http://theory.isthereason.com/?p=499">thingy</a>” that posts my daily <a href="http://del.icio.us/third">del.icio.us links</a> to my blog.  I have been trying to add a pithy description to each of my links so as to explain them in a little more detail than is possible with just the page name.  Enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Q&A With Pandora.com Founder Tim Westergren]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2006/09/qa-with-pandoracom-founder-tim-westergren/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-05T20:45:27-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2006/09/qa-with-pandoracom-founder-tim-westergren</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just returned from <a href="http://blog.pandora.com/pandora/archives/2006/09/flashify_and_wi.html">an amazing Q&amp;A; session</a> with <a href="http://pandora.com/">Pandora.com</a> founder Tim Westergren.  Over the course of an hour and half, Tim told the history of his company and what they are doing today, and answered numerous questions from the audience.  The questions varied greatly, from dealing with Pandora’s business model to querying about the technical backend of the Music Genome Project.</p>

<p>The most interesting questions came from people who wanted to know about new features and the future of the service with respect to the end user.  The two greatest features that were discussed were a notification system for when bands tour in your area, and feedback to the user on his or her stored tastes, both from listening habits and the thumbs up / thumbs down ratings that the user has given.  Pandora already has a band-on-tour monitor, so I’m sure it will not be too hard to move that to a location-based tool.  The more exciting feature, in my opinion, is the user feedback from the system itself.</p>

<p>To have feedback on the type of user that Pandora thinks you are, and, more importantly, the ability to tweak this opinion (I’m thinking adjustable sliders of certain prominent music genes, with respect to the interface) would be amazing.  Not only would you get to specify bands and songs that you enjoy, but you would be able to easily tell Pandora what exactly it is about that band or song that you like.</p>

<p>In any case, it was a great presentation from Tim, and I gained a lot of insight to what it takes to see a startup company through good times and rough times.</p>

<p>One last thing:  Tim mentioned to us that there will be a feature overhaul coming in about two weeks’ time.  Be sure to look out for that!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[30 Boxes Todo List]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2006/05/30-boxes-todo-list/"/>
    <updated>2006-05-04T20:25:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2006/05/30-boxes-todo-list</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Continuing on my <a href="http://thomas.fiveuptons.com/blog/?p=72">endless</a> <a href="http://thomas.fiveuptons.com/blog/?p=78">calendar</a> <a href="http://thomas.fiveuptons.com/blog/?p=80">fixation</a>, <a href="http://30boxes.com/">30 Boxes</a> just implemented a todo list to their calendar software.  The bottom line?  It’s awesome.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/third/140539185/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/54/140539185_46fa935ca9_o.png" alt="30 Boxes Todo" /></a></p>

<p>You can add todo list items with 30 Boxes’ One Box quick add parsing, and add tags to each item.  A new menu item at the top left of the calendar view lets you quickly see and edit your list.</p>

<p>Drag and drop reordering has been implemented, along with double-click-to-edit and a replaced contextual menu functionality.  If you need to push todo events onto a calendar, the option is right there.  Now, notice that I didn’t say “your calendar” or “the calendar,” because 30B has provided options to post to <a href="http://calendar.yahoo.com/">Yahoo! Calendar</a> and <a href="http://calendar.google.com">Google Calendar</a>.</p>

<p>Now, just move that drag and drop functionality to the main calendar and let me preface todo items with @todo in the main One Box entry form for even quicker adding, and we can really start Getting Things Done!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
