<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Films | Uptonian Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/categories/films/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-21T15:15:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Upton]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Christopher Nolan's "Other" Movies]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/2012/01/christopher-nolans-other-movies"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T21:33:42-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/2012/01/christopher-nolans-other-movies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first Christopher Nolan movie I saw was the incredible <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0209144/"><em>Memento</em></a>. I’ve watched it many times since, and I always manage to catch something new. It’s a great movie the first and tenth time you watch it. It’s well-written – with some help from his brother Jonathan, who has helped out on other films since – and the attention to detail is incredible. </p>

<p>I think Nolan caught the attention of most of the movie-going public for his reboot of the Batman franchise. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0372784/"><em>Batman Begins</em></a> is one of the best comic book translations, outdone only by its sequel, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0468569/"><em>The Dark Knight</em></a>. Nolan wisely decided to take breaks between Batman films to make other films that he was interested in. He managed to pull this off because of his own production company, Syncopy Films, and his success as a director. As a result we’ve got two great films so far: <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0482571/"><em>The Prestige</em></a> and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1375666/"><em>Inception</em></a>.</p>

<p>I love that Nolan has focused on other projects that he’s passionate about to avoid creating anything “stale” or boring. I think there’s a larger lesson there that most people can take away. Sometimes you can make something better by <em>not</em> giving it attention.</p>

<p>If Nolan’s “interstitial” movies keep improving at the same rate, we’re in for a treat in 2014.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doom]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/2006/04/doom"/>
    <updated>2006-04-23T21:19:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/2006/04/doom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0419706/">Worst movie</a>.  Ever.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Great Films]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/2006/03/some-great-films"/>
    <updated>2006-03-14T22:36:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/2006/03/some-great-films</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought and watched <a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0399146/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnx0dD0xfGZiPXV8cG49MHxrdz0xfHE9YSBoaXN0b3J5IG9mIHZpb2xlbmNlfGZ0PTF8bXg9MjB8bG09NTAwfGNvPTF8aHRtbD0xfG5tPTE_;fc=1;ft=20;fm=1">A History Of Violence</a> this evening, and I was reminded that I have seen some amazing films recently.</p>

<p>I saw <a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0365737/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnx0dD0xfGZiPXV8cG49MHxrdz0xfHE9c3lyaWFuYXxmdD0xfG14PTIwfGxtPTUwMHxjbz0xfGh0bWw9MXxubT0x;fc=1;ft=23">Syriana</a>  over winter break, and, while I had to see it twice to really get it, I enjoyed the film.  When I saw a post on <a href="http://boingboing.net/">Boing Boing</a> about <a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0404390/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnx0dD0xfGZiPXV8cG49MHxrdz0xfHE9cnVubmluZyBzY2FyZWR8ZnQ9MXxteD0yMHxsbT01MDB8Y289MXxodG1sPTF8bm09MQ__;fc=1;ft=21;fm=1">Running Scared</a>, I was immediately enthralled.  I saw it opening night with my dad, and we both thought that while it was over the top, it was still a good film.</p>

<p>After watching the Oscars (something I haven’t done for two or three years,) I realized that I was missing some great films.  I rented and loved <a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0375679/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnx0dD0xfGZiPXV8cG49MHxrdz0xfHE9Y3Jhc2h8ZnQ9MXxteD0yMHxsbT01MDB8Y289MXxodG1sPTF8bm09MQ__;fc=1;ft=206;fm=1">Crash</a> so much that I watched it twice.  I also really enjoyed watching <a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0358273/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnx0dD0xfGZiPXV8cG49MHxrdz0xfHE9d2FsayB0aGUgbGluZXxmdD0xfG14PTIwfGxtPTUwMHxjbz0xfGh0bWw9MXxubT0x;fc=1;ft=21;fm=1">Walk The Line</a> with my wonderful girlfriend over Spring Break, and consequently started listening to a lot more Johnny Cash!  I borrowed <a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0387131/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnx0dD0xfGZiPXV8cG49MHxrdz0xfHE9dGhlIGNvbnN0YW50IGdhcmRlbmVyfGZ0PTF8bXg9MjB8bG09NTAwfGNvPTF8aHRtbD0xfG5tPTE_;fc=1;ft=16">The Constant Gardener</a> from my parents, and I loved that.  Like Syriana, I may have to watch it again to fully comprehend it, but I thought it was amazingly well done.  I also recently saw <a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0445620/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnx0dD0xfGZiPXV8cG49MHxrdz0xfHE9cGFyYWRpc2Ugbm93fGZ0PTF8bXg9MjB8bG09NTAwfGNvPTF8aHRtbD0xfG5tPTE_;fc=1;ft=20;fm=1">Paradise Now</a> and <a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0344510/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnx0dD0xfGZiPXV8cG49MHxrdz0xfHE9QSBWZXJ5IExvbmcgRW5nYWdlbWVudHxmdD0xfG14PTIwfGxtPTUwMHxjbz0xfGh0bWw9MXxubT0x;fc=1;ft=21;fm=1">A Very Long Engagement</a> at the independent theatre <a href="http://www.thelyric.com/">The Lyric</a> in Blacksburg, and I loved them both.</p>

<p>Along with A History Of Violence, which I thought was amazing, I also bought <a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0433383/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnx0dD0xfGZiPXV8cG49MHxrdz0xfHE9Z29vZCBuaWdodCBhbmQgZ29vZCBsdWNrfGZ0PTF8bXg9MjB8bG09NTAwfGNvPTF8aHRtbD0xfG5tPTE_;fc=1;ft=21">Good Night, And Good Luck</a>.  I have high expectations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Donnie Darko]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/2005/02/donnie-darko"/>
    <updated>2005-02-18T02:11:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/2005/02/donnie-darko</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0246578/">Donnie Darko</a> is an amazing film.  I didn’t find out about it until December 2004, three years after it orignially hit US theatres, and I am ashamed for it.</p>

<p>On the surface it seems to be a teenage story of a confused kid and his visions.  A second and third viewing reveal this movie to be much more.  Although it comes across as a rather pretentious film, the symbolism and imagery are just too vivid to ignore.  A quick (or involved) visit to the <a href="http://www.donniedarko.com/">web site</a> gives you an inkling of what this film entails.</p>

<p>I’m not going to post a plot summary here; you have to go out and watch this film yourself.  Do yourself a favor and watch the original first, followed by the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/B0006GAOBI/qid=1112589613/sr=8-1/ref=pd_csp_1/104-4190662-4857520?v=glance&amp;s=dvd&amp;n=507846">Director’s Cut</a> a day or two later.</p>

<p>–</p>

<p>“Donnie Darko?  What the hell kind of name is that?  It’s like you’re some sort of superhero or something.”</p>

<p>“What makes you think I’m not?”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
