<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: drinks | Uptonian Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/categories/drinks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-29T15:04:45-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Upton]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aeropress]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/2012/07/aeropress"/>
    <updated>2012-07-01T00:07:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/2012/07/aeropress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8161/7476327252_8acfa39cbb_z_d.jpg" alt="Aeropress" /></p>

<p>I don’t think I’ll be using my Keurig much anymore.</p>

<p>I’m extremely late to this party, but I only recently discovered Aerobie’s <a href="http://aerobie.com/products/aeropress.htm">Aeropress</a>
coffee maker.  Yes, the company that created <a href="http://aerobie.com/products/pro.htm">those amazing ring-shaped flying discs</a>
also sells a weird-looking coffee maker. This plunger-like contraption helps to brew what is
probably the best cup of coffee I have ever tasted.</p>

<p>At first glance, it’s similar to a French press, but because the coffee is forced through a paper
filter instead of a coarser wire mesh, there is little to no sediment in the resulting liquid. The
coffee is described as “espresso-strength,” and I drink it as an Americano by adding a volume of
water equal to two times the amount of espresso. I’ve made Aeropress coffe with dark and lighter
roasts, and every cup of coffee has been exquisite.</p>

<p>If you enjoy coffee <em>at all</em>, I highly suggest you acquire an Aeropress as soon as possible. Once
you taste its delicious brew, you’ll understand why. It’s inexpensive, quick, easy to clean, and
delicious. There are no downsides.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/2012/01/coffee"/>
    <updated>2012-01-07T14:37:42-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/2012/01/coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7164/6654753833_ab1c242b36_z_d.jpg" alt="Coffee" /></p>

<p>Like <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OTVE5iPMKLg">most of the world</a>, I love coffee. I usually drink a cup or two a day, and sometimes more. I’m lucky enough to live close to places that sell great coffee: Whole Foods roasts their own coffee, and there are numerous local places with great beans.</p>

<p>I usually make a full “batch” of coffee in a French press (or <em>сafetière</em>), but sometimes that’s too much. I know it’s considered blasphemous, but I got a Keurig single cup brewer for Christmas, and I absolutely love it. I was apprehensive about Keurig machines until I found out about refillable “K-Cups” that you could fill with your own, delicious coffee. I use the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000DLB2FI/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag;=thomupto-20&linkCode;=as2&camp;=1789&creative;=390957&creativeASIN;=B000DLB2FI">official Keurig “My K-Cup”</a>, but that requires that you replace the entire holster mechanism each time. It’s not time consuming, but it is a bit annoying.</p>

<p>I discovered the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/ekobrew-Refillable-Keurig-Brewers-1-Count/dp/B0051SU0OW/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&qid;=1325967276&sr;=8-1">Ekobrew</a>, which is a filter that fits in the existing cup holster. Two of them are on their way to my house from Amazon right now.</p>

<p>Regardless of how it gets there, coffee from the Keurig is (perhaps surprisingly) pleasant. It’s not the best cup of coffee, but it’s quick, easy, and clean.</p>

<p>I still use the French press when I need to make a bigger batch of coffee or if I want to relax and enjoy a really great cup. I use the seemingly-ubiquitous Bodum French press and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0043095WW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag;=thomupto-20&linkCode;=as2&camp;=1789&creative;=390957&creativeASIN;=B0043095WW">burr grinder</a> and keep the coffee warm in my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00004S56U/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag;=thomupto-20&linkCode;=as2&camp;=1789&creative;=390957&creativeASIN;=B00004S56U">Zojirushi carafe</a>. Coffee stays <em>hot</em> for hours on end, so I can make coffee in the morning and still enjoy it later in the afternoon. How I make coffee just depends on how much I need and what kind of mood I’m in.</p>

<p>One last thing: I also got a small stovetop espresso maker for Christmas, and it is amazing. When I want a treat, I make myself a café Americano: a bit of espresso in a normal-sized coffee cup and filled the rest of the way with hot water. Yum!</p>

<p><em>Full disclosure</em>: I’ve linked to a number of products on Amazon in this post, and most of them contain my affiliate link. I’ll get a small kickback if anything is bought via these links. I will only ever post links to products that I use and love, and that is certainly the case with everything here. I’m passionate about my coffee, and I don’t want to mislead anyone. I have not included my affiliate link to the Ekobrew refillable K-Cup because I have not received or used it at this time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
