<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Design | Uptonian Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tupton.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-18T22:57:35-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://tupton.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Upton]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Beginnings]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2009/02/new-beginnings/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-25T22:24:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2009/02/new-beginnings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>I recently started working at [Mailtrust](http://www.mailtrust.com/ “Business Email Hosting &amp; Webmail Services</td>
      <td>Mailtrust”) in Blacksburg, VA. Mailtrust is a division of <a href="http://www.rackspace.com/" title="Dedicated Server - Dedicated Server Hosting - Managed Dedicated Server by Rackspace">Rackspace</a>, a company that has been experiencing some astounding growth recently. One of the companies that Rackspace recently acquired is <a href="http://www.slicehost.com/" title="Slicehost - VPS Hosting">Slicehost</a>. Last week, I decided to sign up for Slicehost hosting and move my website to this new server. I also decided to buy a new domain, <strong>thomasupton.com</strong>. I spent the last week or so setting up my server just how I wanted it.</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>I followed the excellent <a href="http://articles.slicehost.com/" title="Slicehost Article Repository - VPS setup, servers, Ruby on Rails, Django, PHP, DNS, Slicemanager and more">Slicehost articles</a> in order to get started. Setup is a breeze because you have total control over your server. When I screwed something up shortly after starting the setup process, I simply rebuilt and re-imaged my slice and started over.</p>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>The articles for [Ubuntu 8.10](http://www.ubuntu.com/getubuntu/download “Download Ubuntu</td>
      <td>Ubuntu”) are presented in a useful order and detail how to set up and secure a new slice, install Apache to serve websites, and install MySQL and PHP to start getting things done.</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>By far the hardest part of setting all of this up was the migration of my <a href="http://wordpress.org/" title="WordPress › Blog Tool and Publishing Platform">Wordpress</a> installation. I spent a lot of time trying to export a MySQL dump of my existing Wordpress database and import onto my slice. It turns out that <a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2006/06/12/xml-import-export/" title="XML Import / Export « Blog « WordPress.com">Wordpress supports an extended XML-based format for importing and exporting</a> almost every bit of user-created content, including posts, comments, and pages. Existing URL structures are preserved, and author data can be changed to an existing author in the new installation. This was <em>much</em> easier to do than my attempt to directly import a MySQL dump.</p>

<p>After I installed and migrated Wordpress, I decided that I wanted to redesign the look of the site. I wanted an article-centric design that took a minimalist approach to the extreme. What I needed was a skeleton Wordpress template that had useful, semantic markup that was easily customizable. Enter <a href="http://www.plaintxt.org/themes/sandbox/" title="Sandbox plaintxt.org">Sandbox</a>. After activating the theme, designing a layout purely in CSS was extremely easy, thanks in large part to the clear and concise HTML markup. I’m still tweaking the design here and there, and I want to add a dedicated Archives page, but I’m really happy with how the site has turned out so far.</p>

<p>As I mentioned a couple of weeks ago, my interest was rekindled in <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/" title="Tumblr">Tumblr</a> after the release of version five. Tumblr supports custom domains, so I’ve moved my tumblelog to <a href="http://thisis.thomasupton.com/" title="This Is Thomas">This Is Thomas</a>.</p>

<p>I’m really hoping to have more time to blog about issues and topics that I care about now that I don’t have class and homework to worry about. The site is continually undergoing changes in design and structure as I learn more about how to write and design more effectively.</p>

<p>Enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tumblr]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2009/01/tumblr/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-18T00:00:31-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2009/01/tumblr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I <a href="http://thisis.thomasupton.com/">recently started using my Tumblr tumblelog</a> a lot more.</p>

<p>I created my <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a> account some time last year, like everyone else. I linked my <a href="http://delicious.com/third">Delicious feed</a> and this blog to it and promptly forgot about it. I recently realized that there are photos that <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/third/favorites/">I favorite on Flickr</a>, and videos that I <a href="http://www.youtube.com/profile?user=tdmupton&view;=favorites">favorite on YouTube</a> or <a href="http://vimeo.com/user214820/likes">like on Vimeo</a>, and quotes that I see on many different web pages, and chats that I have with my friends that I think other friends would enjoy, but I can’t share them in one central place and oh my goodness I’ve just described the entire reason for Tumblr’s being.</p>

<p>So I added the <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/goodies">Tumblr bookmarklet</a> to my browser’s bookmark bar, and now my favorite things that I come across on the web are all located in one place.</p>

<p>One of the greatest features of Tumblr is the fact that each tumblelog is connected. I can favorite a post right from its permalink, and I can <a href="http://www.kungfugrippe.com/">follow</a> <a href="http://behindtherabbit.tumblr.com/">those</a> <a href="http://lonelysandwich.com/">who</a> I <a href="http://yourmonkeycalled.com/">find</a> <a href="http://clips.43folders.com/">interesting</a>.</p>

<p>I spent a lot of time over the past two days tweaking <a href="http://danny-garcia.com/">Danny Garcia’s</a> <a href="http://lightgrid.tumblr.com/">LightGrid theme</a> to my liking and in the general look and feel of my tumblelog.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blog Comment Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2008/04/blog-comment-design/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-24T16:24:47-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2008/04/blog-comment-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I updated my blog comments from the <a href="http://warpspire.com/hemingway">Hemingway</a> default to a more iconic design.</p>

<p>A <a href="http://css-tricks.com/better-ordered-lists-using-simple-php-and-css/">post about blog comments</a> that I saw a few weeks ago inspired me to use the “big number” idea for my own comments.</p>

<p>I also enabled <a href="http://en.gravatar.com/">Gravatars</a> and have highlighted my own comments when I make them. I have posted the comment loop and the relevant comment CSS in case anyone else wants to use this idea.</p>

<p>This is the comment loop in comments.php. You can <a href="http://www.thomasupton.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/comment-snippetphp.zip">download it as a PHP snippet</a>.</p>

<ol>
  <li>

    <pre><code>			date_format() . '.y' ) ?&gt; / 
				
			
			


				
			comment_approved == '0') : ?&gt;
			_Your comment is awaiting moderation._
</code></pre>

    <p>comment_status) : ?&gt;</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Comments are closed.</p>

<p>This is the CSS section for my comments. You can <a href="http://www.thomasupton.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/comment-snippet.css">download it as a CSS snippet</a>.</p>

<pre><code>/* Comments */
ol#comments li .content span.number {
	position: relative;
	top: 0px;
	left: 0px;
	font-size: 10em;
	color: #c7c7c7;
	float: right;
}

ol#comments li {
	padding: 10px 0;
}

ol#comments li.blog-author {
	background-color: #ddd;
}

ol#comments li.alt .content {
	background-color: #ddd;
}

ol#comments li cite span.date a {
	text-decoration: none;
}

ol#comments li cite span.gravatar {
	margin-top: 13px;
}

ol#comments li cite span.gravatar img {
	padding: 3px;
	border: 1px solid #ccc;
}
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Site Layout]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2008/03/new-site-layout/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-30T15:29:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2008/03/new-site-layout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I changed my blog layout to the <a href="http://warpspire.com/hemingway">Hemingway theme</a> and directed Wordpress to publish to the root of my section of <a href="http://fiveuptons.com">FiveUptons.com</a>.</p>

<p>I am now using Wordpress plugins to display <a href="http://rick.jinlabs.com/code/delicious/">my del.icio.us bookmarks</a>, <a href="http://rick.jinlabs.com/code/lastfm/">Last.fm tracks</a>, and <a href="http://eightface.com/wordpress/flickrrss/">Flickr photos</a>.</p>

<p>To all three of my readers out there, please let me know if there are any issues with the new layout and presentation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Naked Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://tupton.github.com/blog/2006/04/css-naked-day/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-05T09:25:14-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://tupton.github.com/blog/2006/04/css-naked-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While <a href="http://naked.dustindiaz.com/">the concept</a> is nice, I really hate going to everyone’s blog and not being able to see these wonderful designs that everyone is so proud of.</p>

<p>Over at <a href="http://www.stylegala.com/news/public200604/1617.htm">Stylegala</a> there is an interesting comment thread about this idea.  Sure, the underlying XHTML is very important.  I even disabled my stylesheets in Firefox and fixed a couple errors in my markup that I wasn’t happy with. One could argue that this is the point of CSS Naked Day, but I don’t see the point in shoving it in every user’s face.</p>

<p>I can’t wait for 6th April, the CSS Renaissance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
