<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Howto, | Uptonian Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/categories/howto-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-17T20:05:58-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Upton]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Batch Deleting Last.fm Scrobbles]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.thomasupton.com/2012/08/batch-deleting-last-fm-scrobbles"/>
    <updated>2012-08-12T20:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.thomasupton.com/2012/08/batch-deleting-last-fm-scrobbles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently came home from a trip and synced my iPhone in iTunes in an attempt to scrobble the music
that I listened to on that trip. I use <a href="http://meloapp.com/faq/">Melo</a> to scrobble tracks played in iTunes, and it usually
works quite well because I never know it’s there.</p>

<p>I’m not entirely sure if Melo, iTunes, or <a href="http://last.fm/">Last.fm</a> is to blame, but I ended up with a large amount of
scrobbles from a repeated handful of songs. I have over 75,000 tracks scrobbled in Last.fm, but I
use their recommendations and like to look at my stats, so artificially inflating my scrobble
count with three artists was extremely undesirable.</p>

<p>I had 59 pages of unwanted scrobbles; I needed to quickly delete nearly 3000 scrobbles. Last.fm
doesn’t have a way to batch delete (or otherwise manage) your scrobble tracks, so I manually clicked
all the delete links on the first page.</p>

<p>That got old before I had even deleted ten scrobbles. I figured out a way to programmatically and
quickly delete a page of scrobbles. I still have to manually get to each page, but this makes it
much easier.</p>

<p><code>javascript
    jQuery('#deletablert a.delete').each(function(_, a) {
        a.click();
    });
</code></p>

<p>I just open up the console with <code>⌘-⌥-I</code>, paste in that snippet of code, and hit enter. Here is what
it looks like in action.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8282/7770297078_73fafc7541_o_d.png" alt="Batch deleting Last.fm scrobbles." title="Last.fm Batch Delete" /></p>

<p>Since <a href="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</a> is already embedded in Last.fm’s pages, I just select all the delete links and
emit a click on each one. The entire page is deleted in a few seconds. When it’s done, I can click
the link to the previous page and repeat.</p>

<p>I don’t expect this will be very useful to anyone but myself for the next ten minutes, but it could
come in handy in case you’ve been listening to too much Carly Rae Jepsen.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
